Guide to the David Reffkin Ragtime Machine Collection ARS.0121
Archive of Recorded Sound
David Reffkin Ragtime Machine Collection
1981-2007
ARS.0121
Reffkin, David
71 boxes: 1332 tapes stored "pancake" in 10.5" boxes
Archive of Recorded Sound
The Ragtime Machine was a weekly one-hour radio program about ragtime music, produced and hosted by David Reffkin and broadcast on the University of San Francisco's station KUSF. The collection contains all programs from 1981 to 2007, as well as program logs describing their contents, including guests interviewed and songs played.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Source
The David Reffkin Ragtime Machine Collection was donated to the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound by David Reffkin in 2005.
Scope and Contents
Ragtime authority David Reffkin is a researcher, author, and musician. The Ragtime Machine was a radio program about ragtime music, produced and hosted by Reffkin on University of San Francisco radio station KUSF beginning in 1981. The show, which is not currently broadcast (due to the university having sold the station's frequency in early 2011), featured live and recorded performances and interviews, some of which were transcribed and published in the magazine Mississippi Rag. Notable guests featured on the program include Rudi Blesh, Sam and Ann Charters, Patricia Lamb Conn (Joseph Lamb's daughter), Phil Elwood, Donita Fowler (Scott Joplin's niece), Johnny Guarnieri, John Hasse, Dick Hyman, David Jasen, Carl Sonny Leyland, Johnny Maddox, Bob Milne, Mike Montgomery, Max Morath, Joan Morris, Wally Rose, Lalo Schifrin, Gunther Schuller, Ed Sprankle, Butch Thompson, Trebor Tichenor, Craig Ventresco, Ian Whitcomb, and Dick Zimmerman. There are 1350 hour-long programs on 1332 tapes in the collection, which is complete through July 2007; however, the tapes were also transferred to compact disc by Reffkin prior to accession. Programs are numbered, and a copy of the complete program logs is on file in the Archive.
Ragtime machine (Radio program).; Radio programs; Ragtime music
- Tapes, 1332 open reel tapes
  - 1-37 (Audio 1)
  - 38-55 (Audio 2)
  - 56-75 (Audio 3)
  - 76-94 (Audio 4)
  - 95-113 (Audio 5)
  - 114-132 (Audio 6)
  - 133-151 (Audio 7)
  - 152-170 (Audio 8)
  - 171-189 (Audio 9)
  - 190-208 (Audio 10)
  - 209-227 (Audio 11)
  - 228-246 (Audio 12)
  - 247-265 (Audio 13)
  - 266-284 (Audio 14)
  - 285-303 (Audio 15)
  - 304-322 (Audio 16)
  - 323-341 (Audio 17)
  - 342-360 (Audio 18)
  - 361-379 (Audio 19)
  - 380-398 (Audio 20)
  - 399-417 (Audio 21)
  - 418-436 (Audio 22)
  - 437-455 (Audio 23)
  - 456-474 (Audio 24)
  - 475-493 (Audio 25)
  - 494-512 (Audio 26)
  - 513-531 (Audio 27)
  - 532-550 (Audio 28)
  - 551-569 (Audio 29)
  - 570-588 (Audio 30)
  - 589-607 (Audio 31)
  - 608-626 (Audio 32)
  - 627-645 (Audio 33)
  - 646-664 (Audio 34)
  - 665-683 (Audio 35)
  - 684-702 (Audio 36)
  - 703-721 (Audio 37)
  - 722-740 (Audio 38)
  - 741-759 (Audio 39)
  - 760-778 (Audio 40)
  - 779-797 (Audio 41)
  - 798-816 (Audio 42)
  - 817-835 (Audio 43)
  - 836-854 (Audio 44)
  - 855-873 (Audio 45)
  - 874-892 (Audio 46)
  - 893-911 (Audio 47)
  - 912-930 (Audio 48)
  - 931-949 (Audio 49)
  - 950-968 (Audio 50)
  - 969-987 (Audio 51)
  - 988-1006 (Audio 52)
  - 1007-1025 (Audio 53)
  - 1026-1044 (Audio 54)
  - 1045-1063 (Audio 55)
  - 1064-1082 (Audio 56)
  - 1083-1101 (Audio 57)
  - 1102-1120 (Audio 58)
  - 1121-1139 (Audio 59)
  - 1140-1158 (Audio 60)
  - 1159-1177 (Audio 61)
  - 1178-1196 (Audio 62)
  - 1197-1215 (Audio 63)
  - 1216-1234 (Audio 64)
  - 1235-1253 (Audio 65)
  - 1254-1272 (Audio 66)
  - 1273-1291 (Audio 67)
  - 1292-1310 (Audio 68)
  - 1311-1329 (Audio 69)
  - 1330-1348 (Audio 70)
  - 1349-1350 (Audio 71)
- CD transfers
- Program logs, 4 folders